OP--
死んだか
弥助殿
だ　誰か
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:东吾 king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落 时间轴:wcaster
Someone!
Yasuke-dono!
Is he dead?
実は　若年寄水野実芳様のお屋敷に　蟲が出たらしくてね
An insect has appeared at Minister
Mizuno Saneyoshi-sama's mansion.
水野様は以前にも無涯君に蟲退治を依頼したことがあって
Mizuno-sama once asked Mugai-dono
for an insect extermination,
今回もぜひにと頼まれてきたんだよ
and has requested one again.
なんと　若年寄と言えば　幕府の重鎮
What?
Minister is a very important
position in the shogunate!
そのようなお偉い方から直々の依頼とは
A personal request from someone so high up...
さすがは無涯殿
Mugai-dono is amazing!
で　この蟲奉行所のお勤めは二人一組が基本だからね
And so, since the Insect Magistrate
normally works in pairs,
we'll have you go along, as well.
そこで仁兵衛君　今回のお勤めには　君にも行ってもらう
そう　無涯君がみんなの中から君を指名したんだ
Mugai-kun chose you specifically from the group.
なんと
What?
Mugai-dono wants me as his partner?
あの無涯殿が自分を相方に
Mugai:
What Solitary Eyes See
「無涯　孤高の瞳が追う先は」
Oharu-dono!
お春殿
Oh, Jinbei-sama...
まあ　仁兵衛様
聞いてください　お春殿
Just listen to this—
いや これは　お春殿　失礼を
I'm sorry, Oharu-dono...
B-Bastard, what are you doing...
て　てめぇ　俺たちのお春ちゃんに　何してくれてんだ
...to our Oharu-chan?
Um, well...
いや　これは　その
仁兵衛様
Jinbei-sama!
まあ　仁兵衛様が無涯様の相方に
My, so you'll be Mugai-sama's partner?
はい　お春殿には真っ先にお知らせしたくて
Yes, I wanted you to be the first to know.
初めて出会ったときから　無涯殿は自分の憧れでした
Ever since I met him, I've admired him.
His overwhelming power...
あの圧倒的強さ
無涯殿こそ　まさに夜空に輝く綺羅星
He is a star, shining in the night sky!
いつか自分もあの人に認められるような強い男になり
I want to be strong like he is,
to someday repay the favor he did for me.
ご恩に報いたい
そのチャンスがついに
And now I have that chance!
Congratulations, Jinbei-sama.
おめでとうございます　仁兵衛様
お　お春殿
O-Oharu-dono...
Thank you!
ありがとうございます
ああ　仁兵衛様
Jinbei-sama!
無涯殿
Mugai-dono!
お　お　お　お疲れ様です
H-H-Hello, there!
こ　此度は自分を相方に指名していただき 誠にあり　あり　あ
Th-Th-Thank you so much
for choosing m-m-me...
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall do everything I can
この月島仁兵衛　粉骨砕身の覚悟で臨みますので
to meet your expectations!
よろしくお願いします
Then, I'll see you there!
では　自分は一足お先に
いいね　無涯君
Listen, Mugai-kun.
昨日も言ったけど　仁兵衛君は
I told you this yesterday,
but Jinbei-kun...
Mugai-kun...
無涯君
Minister Mizuno Saneyoshi's Estate
おお　なんと大きくて立派なお屋敷
What a splendid mansion!
仕える方々もとても立派な御なりで 頼もしそうな人たちばかり
The samurai here are superbly
dressed and all look so strong!
このような場所でしかも無涯殿とお勤めできるとは
I am honored to be here.
And with Mugai-dono, too!
なんたる僥倖
いったたたた
大丈夫ですか
Are you okay?
A samurai?
お侍様
はい　これでよしっと
That should do it.
す　すいません　おらなんかのために
Th-Thank you for this.
いえ　困ってる人を助けるのは　武士の務めですから
No, a samurai's duty is
to assist those in need.
お侍様
Samurai-sama...
おら　ここの奉公人で　弥助って言います
I am a servant here.
My name is Yasuke.
Yasuke-dono, is it?
弥助殿ですか　自分は蟲方の同心で
I am an officer with the Insect Magistrate—
同心無涯殿　只今蟲奉行所よりご到着
Officer Mugai-dono has arrived
from the Insect Magistrate!
おお　行かねば
I must be going...
See you around, Yasuke-dono.
弥助殿　ではまた
あの人が　蟲方
So he's with the Insect Magistrate.
It has been a long time, Mugai-dono.
久しいな　無涯殿
I haven't seen you since I asked you to exterminate the Bear Cicadas.
以前熊蝉退治を依頼した時以来か
いや　あの時は誠に爽快であったぞ
You were splendid then.
Where is the insect?
蟲は
む　無涯殿　実芳様になんて失礼を
Mugai-dono, don't be so rude to Saneyoshi-sama!
It's fine.
よい　よい　無涯殿は相変わらずだな
He hasn't changed a bit.
ところで
By the way,
先ほどよりそこで面妖な面持ちでいる者は何者だ
who is that boy with the strange expression?
Mugai-dono is so amazing...
やはり無涯殿はすごい
若年寄様が相手でも対等なお付き合いをされているとは
Even the Minister treats him as an equal.
あっ　あの　御仁
U-Um, sir?
お　じ　自分は蟲奉行所同心　月島仁兵衛でございます
I-I am Tsukishima Jinbei, an officer
with the Insect Magistrate.
此度は無涯殿の相方として参りました
I am here as Mugai-dono's partner!
おお　無涯殿の相方
Oh, Mugai-dono's partner?
それは心強い
I'm glad to have you here, then.
Th-Thank you!
はっ　はは
そう　無涯殿は自分を選んでくださった　つまり
Mugai-dono chose me,
which means Mugai-dono thinks I can do this.
無涯殿は自分に期待をされている
よーし　やるぞ
Okay, I'll get it done!
Take a look, Mugai-dono.
では　無涯殿
こちらを見てもらおう
Last night,
they were attacked.
昨晩のうちに襲われてな
It seems the insect means to
make this mansion its nest.
どうやら蟲は　この屋敷に巣食うつもりのようじゃ
これは大人蚤だな
This is an Oohitonomi.
い　今の声は
Th-That voice!
これは
This is...
Oohitonomi
Giant Flea (Larva)
な　なんと惨いことを　許せん
Awful...
I'll kill you!
S-So tough...
な　なんて硬さだ
月島殿　その管には気を付けられよ
Tsukishima-dono, beware of that stinger.
すべての血を吸い取られてしまうぞ
It will suck out all your blood.
What?
なに
こ　これが蚤の跳躍
It has a flea's jumping ability?
これだけは絶対に食らってはいけない
I can't let it hit me!
ならば
In that case...
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Splitter!
月島流　富嶽割
いかがでしたか　無涯殿
Did you see that, Mugai-dono?
来るぞ
They're coming.
な　なんと
Wh-What?
久しぶりに見せてもらおうかな　無涯君の戦いぶり
I haven't seen Mugai-kun fight in a long time.
無涯殿の空気が変わった
The air around him changed.
さ　さすがは無涯殿
A-Amazing, Mugai-dono...
我らでは全く敵わなかった蟲どもを一瞬で
We couldn't even scratch them,
but you dispatched them in an instant.
Your skills are simply astonishing!
や　や　相も変わらず凄まじい剣の腕じゃ
月島殿　おぬしもようやってくれた
Tsukishima-dono, you did well, also.
はっ　はは
Y-Your words honor me!
ありがたきお言葉にございます
ともあれ　これで一件落着であるな
Anyway, that's the end of that.
いや　まだだ
No, not yet.
What?
こいつらはすべて幼虫　つまり
These were all larvae.
In other words...
Oohitonomi
Giant Flea (Male)
ま　まさかこいつが親
I-Is this a parent?
There are still so many?
まだこんなに
雄だけか
Only the male?
さ　実芳様
S-Saneyoshi-sama!
Wh-What is it?
な　何事じゃ
申し上げます　炊事場にも巨大な蚤が現れ
A huge flea has appeared in the kitchen, too!
逃げ遅れた奉公人が
One servant wasn't able to escape!
なんじゃと
What?
いかん　皆の者　すぐに助けに行くのじゃ
Go save him, men!
し　しかし
B-But we can't beat them ourselves...
我らの力ではあの蟲はとても
よーし　無涯殿はこちらを頼みます
Okay!
Mugai-dono, you take care of these.
Leave the other to me.
向こうは自分にお任せください
Y-You're going alone?
お　おぬし一人でか
無論
Naturally.
この命にかけても　必ずや助けてまいります
I'll save him, even if it costs my life!
Mugai-dono?
無涯殿
You aren't strong enough.
お前の腕では無理だ　やめておけ
Don't even try.
な　なんと
What?
なんと　なんと
What? What?!
自分なんかの心配までしていただき　ありがとうございます
I'm honored that you would
worry over someone like me!
Don't worry.
ご安心ください
無涯殿の期待に応えるためにも頑張ります
I shall do my best to meet your expectations!
く　来るな
Stay away!
Oohitonomi
Giant Flea (Female)
だ　誰か
Someone!
月島流?富嶽割り
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Splitter!
Insect Magistrate Officer, Tsukishima Jinbei,
蟲奉行所同心　月島仁兵衛
is here to save you.
弥助殿を助けに参上しました
Samurai-sama...
お侍様
無涯殿の期待　武士ならば必ず応える
As a samurai, I must live up to
Mugai-dono's expectations!
I didn't expect you to choose Jinbei-kun.
やー　意外だったよ
まさか無涯君が仁兵衛君を指名するなんて
無涯君も僕と同じで　彼に期待していたんだね
So you have high hopes for him, as do I.
期待？
Hopes?
I have hopes for him?
俺が　期待だと？
無涯君
Mugai-kun...
す　すごすぎる
W-Wow.
あれだけの数の蟲を瞬く間に
He took out all those insects at once.
Mugai-dono, will your partner who
went to the kitchen be safe?
無涯殿　炊事場にいったおぬしの相方は無事であろうか
The fleas here is a male.
ここにいるのは蚤の雄であろう
Which means the one in the kitchen is the female.
であれば　炊事場に現れたのは雌
蚤の夫婦という言葉にあるように
Isn't the female flea much larger
and stronger than the male?
雌は雄より遥かに大きく　手強いのではないか
知らんな
It doesn't matter.
Tsukishima-dono is your partner, isn't he?
月島殿は　おぬしの相方であろう
そのような言い草は
You shouldn't speak of him that way...
I need no partner.
俺に仲間など必要ない
I defeat insects!
ただ蟲を倒す　 それだけが 俺の全てだ
It's my only task.
That is all I am.
やはり　こいつも硬い
This one's really tough, too...
ならば　叩いて砕くのみ
Then I just need to smash its shell!
Strike at one point!
一点重撃
月島流?富嶽突き
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Strike!
しょ　衝撃が突き抜けた
Th-The shock went through it?
W-Wow...
す　すごい
Insect Magistrate Officers are really strong.
これが蟲方の
One more hit.
後一撃
もう一度　富嶽突きを食らわせれば
Just one more Mt. Fuji Strike!
しまった
No!
弥助殿
Yasuke-dono!
お侍様
Samurai-sama!
Watch out!
危ない
Samurai-sama...
お侍様
Stop...
ダメだ
い　言ったはずです　弥助殿は自分が必ずお助けすると
I told you that I'd save you.
お侍様
Samurai-sama...
Samurai-sama!
死んだか
Is he dead?
バカなやつだ
That fool.
Samurai-sama!
お侍様
This way?
こっちか
M-Mugai-dono, I'm sorry!
無　無涯殿　申し訳ありません
自分は無涯殿の期待に応えることができませんでした
I wasn't able to live up to your expectations!
敵を討ち取ることもできず
I was unable to defeat the enemy...
こうして無涯殿を 待つことしかできませんでした
I had to wait for your arrival!
I'm not worth it...
おらなんかのために
お　おらなんかを
I-I'm not worth it!
無　無涯殿
Mugai-dono!
H-He's...
こ　こいつ
無涯殿
Mugai-dono...
誠に　誠に申し訳ありませんでした
I'm so... I'm so sorry!
He's still talking about that?
こいつ　またそんなことを
Don't let it bother you, potato-boy.
気にするな　芋坊主
I never had any expectations for you.
俺はお前に初めから期待していなかった
I won't let you escape.
逃がさん
塵外刀?砕の型
Jingaitou: Rhino Form.
斬
Die.
やるじゃん
Not bad...
腕は落ちてないみたいだね　無涯君
You're as good as ever, Mugai-kun.
無涯殿　月島殿
Mugai-dono, Tsukishima-dono...
このたびの一件　たいにであった
Excellent work.
はっ　ははあ
Th-Thank you!
Samurai-sama!
お侍様
Yasuke-dono...
おー　弥助殿
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
このご恩は　一生忘れません
I will never forget what you did for me.
I-It was nothing, really...
とん　とんでもない　自分は何もできずただ立っていただけで
I didn't do anything but stand there.
でも…
But...
And a samurai's duty is to assist those in need.
それに困っている人を助けるのは武士の務めですから
月島仁兵衛様
Tsukishima Jinbei-sama...
What a nice bath...
いいお湯でした
あら　あの二人は…
That's...
む　無涯殿　あの時のお言葉はどういう意味ですか？
Mugai-dono, what did you mean back there?
That you had no expectations for me.
初めから期待していないのだと
言葉通りの意味だ
Just as I said.
で　ではなぜ
Th-Then why?
なぜ無涯殿は　今回の相方に自分を選ばれたのですか
Why did you choose me for this mission?
Then why choose Jinbei-kun?
じゃ君はどうして仁兵衛君を
He is the weakest.
一番弱いやつなら
死んでも替わりは見つけやすいからな
If he dies, he will be easiest to replace.
Mugai-dono!
無涯殿
The reason was...
理由は…
I've forgotten.
忘れた
はい
Huh?
無　無涯殿
M-Mugai-dono...
I don't think th-that's really fair.
そ　それはあまりといえば　あまりのお言葉
Don't tell me you forgot.
忘れたなどとはおっしゃらずに
Tell me why...
理由を
Tell me why you chose me!
自分が選ばれた理由を
I don't really understand why,
よくは分かりませんけど
お二人とも楽しそうですね
but those two seem to be having fun.
Mugai-dono, wait...
無涯殿　待ってください
ちゃんと　ちゃんと理由を
Tell me... Tell me why!
Next Time
I'm searching for suspicious people!
不審者の捜索です
No one in the main room!
ガラガラ　居間　異常なし
No one in the living quarters!
ガラガラ　長屋　異常なし
No one in the women's bath...
ガラガラ　女湯
ちょっと
Hey!
No one here!
異常な～し
You pervert!
このエロすけが
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行　「お面の下のイケメン　長福丸」
The Hot Guy Beneath the Mask: Nagatomimaru.
The Hot Guy Beneath the Mask: Nagatomimaru